<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrick Smyth</title>
    <description>Patrick Smyth is a doctoral student at the CUNY Graduate Center.</description>
    <link>smythp.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="smythp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 13:32:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 13:32:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use Text Expanders for More Efficient Grading</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you grade papers (or proofread) frequently, you probably find yourself writing the same comments over and over:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:none&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Use a synonym here to avoid repetition.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Periods should be inside quotation marks.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I found this section a little unclear. Could you elaborate?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When encountering similar mistakes over dozens of papers, I tend to fall into patterns, using certain phrases and terms to point out and explain problems. After all, there are only so many ways one can indicate that book titles should be italicized, or that “alright” should be “all right.” This often means that I will write a phrase such as “Use a synonym to avoid repetition” in twenty separate papers, which is itself something of a repetitive exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I receive, grade, and return papers electronically, I’ve found a method that alleviates some of the tedium of repeating stock phrases over and over. Text expanders are programs that automatically turn small snippets of text (such as “syn1”) to larger phrases (such as “Use a synonym to avoid repetition.”) By loading up a text expander with a library of frequently-used comments, a essay grader can substantially reduce the amount of typing necessary to leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a text expander to aid in grading has some substantial advantages. Because leaving certain comments becomes easier, one is less tempted to leave cryptic marks (“?” or “!”) or simply underline text to indicate mistakes. While these corrective marks might seem clear to teachers, they are often baffling to students who might not be familiar with the underlying principles to which these marks refer. By freeing up effort usually spent on addressing common mistakes, one often finds it easier to comment on an essay more holistically, responding to the content of the paper rather than focusing exclusively on form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my own grading, the free version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phraseexpress.com/&quot;&gt;PhraseExpress&lt;/a&gt; text expander is more than adequate, although faster and more feature-laden expanders such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/238306/lifehacker-code-texter-windows&quot;&gt;Texter&lt;/a&gt; also exist. In Windows, after installing PhraseExpress, double click its icon in the system tray to bring it up. Hit File &amp;gt; New &amp;gt; Local phrase file to create a new set of phrases that can be backed up and transferred between computers. Then hit CTRL-N to create a new comment template. Type the full version of the comment in the “Phrase Content” box, then add a shortcut phrase (such as “syn1”) to the Autotext box. Hit OK, and repeat for all your frequently used comments. Remember that the short phrase you enter in Autotext should be something you would only type deliberately, or else you will trigger the text expansion automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as you enter comments in paper, simply type your short Autotext phrase (“syn1”) to automatically generate the longer comment (“Use a synonym to avoid repetition”). I usually add different versions of the same general comment for use within the same paper—“syn2” might fill in as “Use a different word here.” You might also load up your expander with some stock examples—“The boy throws the ball.”—to illuminate concepts such as subject-verb agreement or parallel structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text expanders can also be invaluable if you often switch between email signatures, such as when switching between administrative and faculty roles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>smythp.com/teaching/2016/03/04/expanders.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">smythp.com/teaching/2016/03/04/expanders.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eight Reasons to Grade Essays Electronically</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I know, I know, you have a system. But here are eight reasons to go paperless and do your grading electronically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Leave a Paper Trail by Going Paperless&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By having students submit assignments via email, Dropbox, or Blackboard, you automatically have documentation indicating when (or if) students have turned in their work. This can head off many potential disputes and misunderstandings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Handwriting Is Terrible&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_38&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;float: right;margin: 0 0 10px 10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalscholar.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/elder_fu.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-38&quot; alt=&quot;Elder Futhark&quot; src=&quot;http://www.digitalscholar.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/elder_fu-300x102.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;102&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;small-text&quot; style=&quot;margin: 3px;&quot;&gt;If your writing starts looking like this, break out the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might pride yourself on your impeccable penmanship, but even &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wang_Xizhi&quot;&gt;Wang Xizhi&lt;/a&gt; might become indecipherable after marking up his 39th essay. Having a student approach you to clarify what you’ve written can be embarrassing, and some might not even bother to parse your chicken scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Take Control of Your Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marking a paper essay involves cramming comments into margins and between lines. Sometimes serendipity takes over and you just manage to explain subject-verb agreement in the space allotted. More likely, you’ll be forced to cut off something useful, or write so small that you’re flirting with indecipherability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might say that paper grading helps instructors resist the temptation to leave novel-length comments, which are impractical and time-consuming. I would argue that some points need deeper explication, and others (“This phrase is cliché.”) might benefit from a bit of finesse in their delivery. When you grade electronically, the length of your comments is not predetermined, and you can go into as much or as little detail as needed in a section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Provide Links and Supporting Documents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a well-chosen link can be an invaluable supplement to a comment. By giving feedback electronically you can add links to library books, articles, word definitions, or grammar and style guidelines much more readily than you can with pen and paper. I sometimes also add additional style and grammar documentation after my final comments if particular issues cropped up frequently in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Students (And Trees) Prefer Electronic Submissions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 310px;float: right; margin: 0 0 5 0;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalscholar.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/happy-tree.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-37&quot; alt=&quot;Poor little tree&quot; src=&quot;http://www.digitalscholar.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/happy-tree-300x205.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;205&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;small-text&quot;&gt;What did this poor tree ever do to you?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has wrestled with an ornery printer knows that these devices are a fickle breed, liable to become unresponsive, jam, or run out of “cyan ink” in a moment of crisis. By allowing students to send their papers directly to you, you’re making their lives slightly easier. You’re also saving paper, which is made out of the bodies of friendly trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Streamline the Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of tips and tricks that can save you time and effort when grading essays electronically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalscholar.net/?p=24&quot;&gt;Use text expanders to avoid costly repetition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shaunakelly.com/word/sharing/howtrackchangesworks.html&quot;&gt;Use Track Changes in MS Word to create readable markup.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suefrantz.com/2011/02/17/grading-electronically-tips-tricks-and-shortcuts/&quot;&gt;Use keyboard shortcuts and Adobe Acrobat to help with electronic grading.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Teach Your Students New Skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many students have never encountered tools such as Dropbox or MS Word’s Track Changes before and will benefit from a working knowledge of how they function. Track changes, in particular, is used in a number of office environments, and Dropbox and other cloud storage services are becoming increasingly prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Access Reference Materials and Check for Plagiarism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it helps to double check the spelling of a word or to refresh your memory on an obscure grammar rule or citation guideline. When working electronically, it becomes easier to reference these materials and incorporate them into your comments. Finally, in cases of suspected plagiarism, you can copy sections of a paper into a tool such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.copyscape.com/signup.php?pro=1&quot;&gt;Copyscape Premium&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that is more difficult to access when working from a printout.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- .entry-content --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>smythp.com/teaching/2016/03/04/electronically.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">smythp.com/teaching/2016/03/04/electronically.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five Underrated Features in Zotero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Zotero is an excellent citation manager, but it can be so much more. These underused features allow Zotero users to go beyond simply creating bibliographies, transforming Zotero into a platform for reading, visualizing, and storing academic work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Zotero users know that the citation manager can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/getting_stuff_into_your_library&quot;&gt;store local copies of journal articles&lt;/a&gt; accessed on repositories such as JSTOR and Project MUSE. However, Zotero can also be used to store and retrieve ebooks that have been saved to your hard drive. In Zotero Standalone, simply right click an entry for a book and select Add Attachment &amp;gt; Attach Stored Copy of File. Navigate to the location where your ebook is saved and double-click to make the book a permanent part of your Zotero library. The ebook will be stored in a separate folder that is backed up along with your Zotero library, so with this feature you can create an ebook collection that moves with you from computer to computer. For an even stronger collection, use an ebook manager such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://calibre-ebook.com/&quot;&gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt; to convert your ebook to your desired format before storing it in Zotero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature is also a great way to keep track of your own work. Simply create an entry for your paper or publication, and attach a .docx or .pdf of your writing. Whenever you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/zotero_data&quot;&gt;back up your Zotero library&lt;/a&gt;, your past work will also be saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-timeline-of-your-past-work&quot;&gt;Create a Timeline of Your Past Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious about what you were working on back in 2011? Care to see how your academic interests have evolved over the years? Zotero has a built-in timeline feature that will display a visualization of all your interactions with the program over the years. Simply select the collection you would like to visualize (you may want to try the top-level My Library view first) and select Tools &amp;gt; Create Timeline from the menu bar. Navigate the timeline by dragging the hand icon from left to right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the timeline will display the dates of publication of entries you’ve stored. While this may provide a useful insight into the periods your work is drawn from, you may also wish to sort these entries by the dates they were added to your collection. To do this, simply change the item in the Date Type box on the bottom of the screen from Date Published to Date Added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organize-your-library-with-notes-tags-and-related-tabs&quot;&gt;Organize your Library with Notes, Tags, and Related Tabs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underused Notes, Tags, and Related tabs that appear on the right pane when you select an entry allow you to store your thoughts on a text for later and draw parallels across collections. While reading books or articles, I often jot down reactions and observations in Microsoft Word. To make sure I have access to these notes in one central location, I paste these reactions into the form provided under the Notes tab. That way, when I return to the collection weeks, months, or years later, I don’t have to search for a hard-to-find Word document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I do not use the Tags and Related tabs as frequently, they can be useful when creating categories that work across collections. For example, I use a “To Read” tag to denote books and articles that I know I should examine more carefully in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;view-your-zotero-library-by-tablet-or-mobile&quot;&gt;View Your Zotero Library by Tablet or Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it takes some setting up, apps such as Zotero Reader and ZotPad allow you to access your Zotero library even when you’re away from your laptop. This can be invaluable for summer reading, preparing for classes, or quickly refreshing your memory of a colleague’s work at a conference. Check out these tutorials to get yourself up and running on your favorite device:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/mobile&quot;&gt;Zotero Mobile Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zotpad.com/sites/default/files/UserManualWeb.pdf&quot;&gt;ZotPad Manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hastac.org/blogs/craigeley/2013/02/25/ipad-workflow-zotero-zotfile-zotpad&quot;&gt;iPad Workflow: Zotero + Zotfile + ZotPad&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Zotero with Plugins and Add-ons&lt;/h2&gt;

An active community of developers has created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/plugins&quot;&gt;variety of plugins&lt;/a&gt; that can extend Zotero’s functionality. Whether you want to &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/delicious-library-export/&quot;&gt;import items from Delicious into Zotero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/plugins/zotpress/&quot;&gt;integrate Zotero with WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisjr.github.io/papermachines/&quot;&gt;create advanced visualizations&lt;/a&gt;, or simply &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://forums.zotero.org/discussion/18166/zotero-item-history-plugin/&quot;&gt;spruce up Zotero’s GUI&lt;/a&gt;, these add-ons can turn Zotero into a versatile tool for saving, displaying, and exporting data.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

See also:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/tips_and_tricks&quot;&gt;Zotero Tips and Tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://geekandgirliestuff.blogspot.com/2013/03/going-all-in-with-zotero-zotpad-and.html&quot;&gt;Geek and Girlie Stuff Guide to Zotero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://chronicle.com/blogs/profhacker/zotero-vs-endnote/33157&quot;&gt;Zotero vs. Endnote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>smythp.com/underrated_zotero/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">smythp.com/underrated_zotero/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Killer Apps for Digital Scholars</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As academics, we&amp;#8217;re used to dealing with clunky technology. Whether we&amp;#8217;re trying to organize a course on Blackboard or navigate a database with an interface designed in 1997, sometimes it can feel like our tech is working against us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s why it&amp;#8217;s so nice when an app simply &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;. These five applications can make some common tasks considerably easier for the modern scholar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zotero.org/&quot;&gt;Zotero&lt;/a&gt; Citation Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zotero is a citation manager that allows scholars to organize research, create bibliographies, and maintain a personal library. Zotero started out as a Firefox extension, and one of its most impressive features is still its ability to pull full articles and citations from popular databases with one click. The application maintains lists of books and articles that can be readily converted into bibliographies in MLA, APA, or any major citation format. Rival citation manager &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.refworks.com/&quot;&gt;RefWorks&lt;/a&gt; is also worth a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.refworks.com/&quot;&gt;RefWorks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://endnote.com/&quot;&gt;Endnote&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.easybib.com/&quot;&gt;EasyBib&lt;/a&gt; for dilitantes or the half-hearted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://calibre-ebook.com/&quot;&gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calibre is a unified ebook management platform that allows users to integrate their ebook libraries, convert ebook files between formats, and transfer ebooks to various devices. It&amp;#8217;s also handy for reading .epub or .mobi files on a PC or Mac without many of the annoying restrictions one encounters on readers from Adobe, Google, or Amazon. Calibre can also be configured to remove pesky DRM from purchased ebooks, although this accessing this functionality requires some tweaking. In any case, Calibre is the perfect organizational tool for those (like me) who use digital books in their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives: None (Calibre is in a class of its own)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freemind.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;FreeMind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many apps designed for &amp;#8220;mind mapping,&amp;#8221; which is essentially a fancy term for graphics-based outlining. FreeMind is a lightweight mind mapping utility that allows users to sketch ideas visually using a simple interface. It also allows easy exportation of mind maps to other formats, such as PDF and HTML. Great for outlining papers or getting down nascent thoughts before they slip away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives: &lt;a href=&quot;http://coggle.it/&quot;&gt;Coggle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;http://www.xmind.net/&quot;&gt;XMind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/‎&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a cloud-based system for file management is becoming increasingly important for class management, collaboration, and maintaining backup data. Google Drive (formerly Google Docs) and rival &lt;a href=&quot;www.dropbox.com&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; solve a number of problems for the modern academic, and the first time you collaborate on a Doc with another research in real time you&amp;#8217;ll be sold on Google&amp;#8217;s technology. On the other hand, services such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sugarsync.com/#googtrans(en|en)&quot;&gt;SugarSync&lt;/a&gt; offers more space and more storage and sharing features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives: &lt;a href=&quot;www.dropbox.com&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://www.sugarsync.com/#googtrans(en|en)&quot;&gt;SugarSync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khan Academy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good learners make great teachers, and a number of sites have popped up in recent years that allow easy access to new skills and training. One of my personal favorites is Khan Academy, which offers videos and tutorials on a wide variety of topics. Khan Academy is slowly transforming into a digital learning platform that offers assessment and live tutoring in addition to video lectures. This trend is being followed by other digital learning platforms, including Apple&amp;#8217;s &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/apps/itunes-u/?cid=wwa-us-kwg-features-com&amp;amp;siclientid=6381&amp;amp;sessguid=83aba7ce-ceae-4f3a-ab80-eff9d67c80a0&amp;amp;userguid=83aba7ce-ceae-4f3a-ab80-eff9d67c80a0&amp;amp;permguid=83aba7ce-ceae-4f3a-ab80-eff9d67c80a0&quot;&amp;gt;iTunes U. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks&quot;&gt;TED Talks&lt;/a&gt; is another accessible way to stay up-to-date on the latest developments inside and outside academia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>smythp.com/jekyll/update/2015/11/22/killer-apps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">smythp.com/jekyll/update/2015/11/22/killer-apps.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Workarounds for Citing Ebooks</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most scholars in the humanities avoid using e-books for research. The difficulty is mostly citation—one immediately runs into problems when quoting digital editions, and the solutions proposed by MLA and other major arbiters of style are inelegant at best.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary difficulty lies in determining page numbers. When working from a scanned book, essentially a facsimile of the print edition, finding a page number is not a problem, since pages are of a uniform size across devices and display modes. But flowing text file formats such as .mobi and .epub do not generally display standardized page numbers. Instead, page numbers differ based on font, screen size, text size, and myriad other factors. The result is that every user sees different page numbers, and these numbers are therefore useless in citation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mla.org/style/style_faq/mlastyle_cite_an_ebook&quot;&gt;MLA recommends&lt;/a&gt; that writers use other markers, such as chapter heading, instead of the page number in parenthetical citations and bibliographies. Besides its imprecision, this solution also lacks a certain aesthetic appeal. It&amp;#8217;s a stop-gap fix, and the lack of a proper method of e-book citation leads most academics in the humanities to prefer print books to e-books when conducting serious research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet there is some hope for those who wish to continue using e-books for writing and research. Here are two workarounds for quoting digital editions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google Books Wordaround&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method involves taking the quote you&amp;#8217;ve found in an e-book and tracking down the corresponding print location using the search function in Google Books. First, navigate to &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Books&lt;/a&gt; and enter the name of the book you wish to quote. Pick a print edition of the book from the resulting list, if available. Next, copy a snippet of the text you wish to quote and paste it into the small search field on the left side of the book description. This should bring up the page in the print edition that corresponds to your quote, and you can then use that page number in an in-text citation. Finally, construct a bibliography entry based on the print edition of the book rather than the digital edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of this method is that it results in a precise page number and a standard MLA print citation. However, it also adds an extra step in the citation process and it works only for the books that have been digitized by Google. Some scholars also find this process a bit disingenuous. Their reasoning is that if you use an e-book in your research, your bibliography should reflect that, and that switching between the forms can introduce discrepancies. However, my feeling is that Google Books allows one to check for differences between print and e-book editions before including a quote in your writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kindle Position&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re using the Kindle edition of an e-book, you can quote Kindle Position instead of page number. If you have a book open in your Kindle desktop application, simply copy the text you wish you quote and paste it into your word processing program or web app. The pasted text should show the Kindle Position(s) for the text you selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is more precise than the MLA&amp;#8217;s proposed solution of citing chapter headings, but it has its own problems. Many scholars aren&amp;#8217;t familiar with Kindle editions, so your citation might stand out as odd to colleagues or peer reviewers. On the other hand, if you&amp;#8217;re working in the digital humanities or a field related to technology, Kindle Position might be viewed as an acceptable alternative to page numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;		&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-- .entry-content --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;footer class=&quot;entry-meta&quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
		
		
			&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>smythp.com/underrated_zotero/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">smythp.com/underrated_zotero/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
